On Ukraine's Independence Day,
two women also wore embroidered shirts, and they were
forced to apologize.  Yes.  Well, I think this is
normal.  Well, that is to say, for me
it’s just normal.  Like, if you
apologize, well, like, apologize for this,
detain for that.  I think this is
normal.  In terms of?
Well, the fact that they were detained in Yalta, well,
you were telling stories just now.
Is this normal
for me?  Yes.  For me it's normal.
The girls sang the song simply in
Ukrainian and for that,
Yes.  Yes.  Well, they should understand what is
normal for you?
They must understand the scale of the
problem.
And I just despise Ukrainians.
Good evening.
Hello.
Where are you from?
I'm from Crimea.
Understood.  I am from Baku.  Azerbaijan.
And for some reason you have Ukraine listed.
Well, VPN, because there is no Azerbaijan
in chat roulette.  You need to choose another
country.  Build a VPN.   What are
you even talking about?
[snorts] I talk to Russians and Ukrainians, and
I can’t quite understand why they’re fighting
, because, well, our
news rarely shows it.
I want to figure out why you have a
war between Russia and Ukraine.   Are
you on any side or
neutral?
I am neutral.
Neutral.  But if, well, honestly, I
probably haven't compiled statistics, but in
general, based on conversations between people from different countries, from
these two countries, there is some kind of greater
balance on the one hand, well, precisely in
terms of adequacy, or somehow everything is both
there and there,
well, it's more pleasant to talk with Ukrainians,
honestly.  They are somehow calmer, yes,
Russians hate us,
Azerbaijanis, a lot, especially in the last
week.
There is a rather aggressive environment there, the
political background has changed, and I
felt it directly on myself.
Well,
the kids shout at me: "Take your
tomatoes to Azerbaijan."
Although I have never been to Russia.
And you, as I understand it, are a Ukrainian who... As
I understand it, you are a Ukrainian who,
like, defected to Russia, right?
No, no, no.  I am a Russian who came
to Russia.  Well, I’m like, “So
, when did you get to Crimea?”
I'm
2018.
What?  2018. Where did you come from?
From Volgograd.
Why did you come to Crimea from Volgograd?
Just curious.  Well, work is about work and
about parenting.
Cool.  What, are your parents some kind of
military men?  No, no, my parents are businessmen.
Understood.  And do you have real estate in
Volgograd or Crimea?
Everywhere, like, scattered throughout the country
.  Well, like, there are some in Volgograd, and
there are some in Crimea, and is
n't it creepy?  There he flies to Crimea.
Well, it's
already creepy.  No, not anymore.   Did
they think that something like this could happen,
that the Russian army would leave Kherson
, and that it would leave Crimea too?
I doubt it.  No,
well, in Kherson they had doubts too.  Anything
can happen now, the political situation
will change.  There Putin will die, uh, his
successor will say that, like, that’s it, we’re giving
you up to improve relations with the world.
Well, if this happens, we will, as they
say, hide from the stove, and wait and
see how the situation goes.  How?  Will you stay there in
Crimea or go to Volgograd?  How do you
see it?
I think we'll leave now.
Understood.
Well, now, now I am Well, in fact,
now I am now I am not in Crimea.
Right now I'm in Volgograd, so for now
I'm kind of going back and forth.  Well, are there
many in Crimea who came to
Crimea from Russia?   Yes.  Yes.
Well, not really very many.  Well, there are
these people, yes.  It turns out that
Russia is populating Crimea with its own people.  Yes, it does
.
Well, yes, yes, yes.
There, well, I don’t often, well, I haven’t
really met those people in personal
conversations who have any kind of
attitude towards Ukraine in general.
That is, although they were born and
raised there, they do not belong to
Ukraine.
Come on, come on, come on, let's agree
that Russia is a police state.
For example, in your country, is it possible to, uh, go to a
rally against Putin?
No.
No?  Yes.  Like this.  With such a person
you will immediately understand that Yes.  So,
a person who is for Ukraine simply
won’t open his mouth, because he
understands what will happen to him now.  Yes.
For example, I watched your video, the girls in
Yalta sang Chervono Kolyna, they were
detained and forced to apologize.  Hey, on
Ukraine's Independence Day, some
two women also wore embroidered shirts, and they were
forced to apologize.  Yes.  Here.  And
well, I think that this is normal.  Well, that is to
say, for me it’s just normal.  Like,
if you apologize, well, like, apologize for this
, detain for that.  I think
this is normal.  In terms of?
Well, the fact that they were detained in Yalta, well,
you were telling stories just now.
This is normal
for me, right?  For me it's normal.
The girls sang the song simply in
Ukrainian and for that.   Yes.  Yes.
But they should understand what is
normal for you?
They must understand the scale of the
problem.
And I simply despise
Ukrainians and
their army.  Well, that is, I can
Look, look, look, people, people, yes,
you came from Volgograd, for these
people you are an occupier, right?
Uh, you support the fact that for the
Ukrainian language, Ukrainian songs, for the
Ukrainian embroidered shirt, national
clothing, yes, they are detained, yes, and
then they are forced to apologize, uh, an
administrative protocol is drawn up against them
, and you think that this is
right.   Yes.   Could
you explain why a woman doesn't have the right to
wear an embroidered shirt in Crimea?
Well, because this is Crimea - this is not
Ukraine.  Crimea is Russia.  And wearing
there what
represents the national
dress of Ukraine, with which there is currently a
conflict, is not...
Well, look, Russia is a
multinational country,
about 5 million ethnic Ukrainians live in it
,
yes.  which was still there during the Soviet Union.
Why can a Tajik wear
his national clothing?  Why is
the Ukrainian higher? So you simply forbid
a person to wear
clothes traditional to his ethnic group?  Yes.
Well, you understand perfectly well that there are no
disagreements with the Sajiks.  And
when there is a
military conflict, when
Russian soldiers are killed by
Ukrainian soldiers, just as Ukrainian soldiers are killed by
Russian soldiers, well, wearing
something in Russia that represents Ukraine
is not...
Yes.  So, I understand correctly, and it’s
not worth speaking Ukrainian
in Russia, yes, for now.  Yes, yes, that's
right.
Why?
for the same reason.
So, it turns out that you, from Russia,
believe that in Russia a person does not have the
right to speak Ukrainian,
right?  He should be arrested for this.
Well, yes, well, just
to arrest him, but no, just to
arrest him and
file an administrative report against him.  Well, probably,
what needs to be done with someone
who speaks Ukrainian in Russia
?
Well, I think everyone gets a second
chance.  And I think it's like a
warning the first time, the second time,
something like that.  This is already, well
, for example, imagine, yes, some
guy or girl, yes, fundamentally
communicates in a public place, yes, in
Ukrainian with another, yes,
Yeah.
And they reprimand him.  He believes that
he has the right to speak and say what
should be done to him.
Here.  Well then, yes, and they should
come to him and say:
“Stop speaking
Ukrainian.”
Why isn't it illegal in your legislation
to speak
Azerbaijani, Ukrainian, or English there?   Yes.
Well, I already explained.
Well, he tells me: "The constitution does not
prohibit speaking Ukrainian."   What
will they say next?
Well, because, well, how can I explain this to you?
Because the fathers and
brothers of many are dying from Ukrainian bullets,
and speaking their language is disrespectful
here.  And, well, for me, for me, they didn’t
allow it.  I understand that you have a
completely different point of view, and you
see it differently, but I tell you,
as a true Russian person, this is
unacceptable to me.  For example, I
have, uh, a
fiancée, and
we're planning a wedding soon.
She's just more skeptical about it
.  She can listen to, you know,
Ukrainian
rap groups there and either agents who did
not support Russia at the beginning of the SVO and
left the Russian Federation.
And I completely forbade
these songs to be played in my presence.  And I never
heard them.  That is, when they turned on
in front of me, I, well,
could raise my voice and say that
this cannot be done.
And he beat the girl if she didn’t turn it off.
Bill.
Well, if she didn’t turn it off, she didn’t want to
turn it off.
No, she, she, she, everything is fine, she
understands everything perfectly.  I say: "No,
you can't. No, never stand with your headphones on in front of me and
listen."  But why didn't I hear this?
Listen, for example, in the
territories captured by Russia, yes, there are a lot of
people there for whom Ukrainian is their
native language.  They
spoke Ukrainian, so it turns out they can't
speak Ukrainian either.
Well, that's a different situation.  Probably,
probably, it is still possible to make exactly these kinds of
exceptions; if you do it, then it is
probably still possible.  Well, it’s not me who has the right
to judge who can and who can’t.  Well, that's just how I
look at the situation, damn.
Well, let them, well, probably, if they can
speak Ukrainian, then
they, well, they can definitely
speak Russian,
because basically all Ukrainians can
speak Russian.   Yes.
But [clears throat] I’m just
curious, how do your opinions fit in with the
Constitution of the Russian Federation?  Yes,
by law a person is not prohibited from
speaking any language.  Ah,
but I don't fit in with the code.  Well, there are
situations in which one
can go against the code.  And I understand it a little
differently.  Well,
I mean, I don't sing like that.  It's just
that with legal entities in
Azerbaijan, you can't go against the
law, even if it's
different.
Well, somehow, you know, you can go
against
the law, and you can be
held responsible for it.  Well,
listen, for example, let's do it this way.  You're
walking down the street, yes,
and a Ukrainian girl, yes, well, not a
Russian girl, yes, sings a song in
Ukrainian, yes.  For example, there was a burning pine
tree there.  Here they have it.  Yes.
Here.  And what will you say to her?
Well, I'll come.  You tell me, well
I'll tell you
to stop
this singing.
And
if she doesn't stop, well, I don't know,
call the police, it's such a situation
that, well, I just can't
understand, yes, how does it work in Russia
, yes, for example, well, you call
the police and what do you say, is there a girl
singing in Ukrainian or what?
Well, yes, I have never had such
situations.  Don't know.  Well, and like, well, I ca
n’t even imagine.  I will
act according to the situation, as it happens
.  Come on, how do you see it, how
can you make her not sing?
Tell him to go and stop singing.  Well, I
think she has a right.   Okay
, I'll
call the police and let them
deal with them.
Well, what about the police, how are they figuring it out?
What violation did the police commit?  Like, she sings
in Ukrainian, it’s not prohibited.
Different languages ​​are spoken freely in Russia.
It seems Ukrainian is not prohibited.
Well, I don't know anymore.  Well, sort of, but
Russia, I think... Oh, Russia, the police, I
think, will still act on
my side more than...
And how could it not?  Well, not the police, they don’t
act on your side or on the
girl’s side.  She acts on the
side of the law.  Well, I should act
on the side of the law, right?  That is, she
comes like this if, for example, you are there, uh,
on a pole, yes, oh, you are disturbing
public order.  If you shout
obscenities, you are disturbing the
peace.  If you speak or
sing in Ukrainian, it is not a
violation.  Well, in
legislation.
Well, what if you have people who
speak Armenian?
We even have a center of Armenian culture in the letter
.
Well, so this is normal for you?   Well, yes
.  Well,
you see, here there are some kind of moral
orders, or something, more.  Well, for you it’s
normal, for us it’s not.  It's just that
different countries act differently.  That
is, for example, in Saudi Arabia,
the same hands and fingers are cut off.
No, I don't understand that.  No, well,
you have a law, right?  You all act
in accordance with the laws of the Russian
Federation, right?  If, for example, you have a
ban on the display of
Nazi symbols, yes, if a girl
displays a swastika, then, of course,
the police will be called.  The police come, oh,
there's a crime, right?  Oh, and if
a girl speaks or sings in
Ukrainian, what's the offense?
What can the police do to her?
Well, for what?  For what?  For what?
And if, well, I’ve never asked myself this
question, honestly.  What if we
ask the Internet now?
Let's ask the Internet.  Interesting.
[laughter]
Question.  Well, you know, like otvet.ru, when
they ask and everyone else answers.
The girl writes: "Is it forbidden to listen to
Ukrainian songs of the VRF?"
For example, if I listen to
Ukrainian songs at home, can this be considered
defamatory?
VSRF or not.  And what kind of music will
discredit the VSR?
Well, listen, listen.
And there is an answer.  No.  Listening to Ukrainian
songs is prohibited in the Russian Federation.
Russian President Vladimir Putin
declared that it is unacceptable
to restrict Ukrainian culture in Russia
and advised against
becoming like those who abolish culture.
He also recalled that Russia is
outraged by
attempts to abolish Russian culture and did not
recommend behaving in the same
way.  Furthermore, Putin also called
the question of the possibility of
abolishing the Ukrainian language in Russia unlawful,
since it is the state language in one of the
subjects of the Russian Federation, for example, Krmul.
Well, listening to Ukrainian songs at home
is not a discrediting of the Russian Federation or
any violation of the law.  There is no such thing as a
private house
on the street.  street, if you listen on the street.
And at
home I understood everything, it’s possible at home.  At home, Putin
allows listening to Ukrainian songs.   Is it
possible to sing in Ukrainian on the street? Is it
possible to sing in Ukrainian on Red
Square
in Moscow?
You obviously don't read Russian well.   There is
no answer here yet.  Now
M, I don’t know, I can’t find it yet.  Well,
there is no clear, precise answer about
this.
Well,
I guess so, after all.
Well, there is no clear answer.  I don't know, I don't
see.
So it turns out that it’s possible to sing
in Ukrainian?
Well, well, I didn’t see a clear answer, but there was an
incident for listening to a
Ukrainian song in the car, and he was detained and
fined 50,000 rubles.
And for what?  In what?  Under what article?
Under what article?  The article was probably,
so to speak, attributed to him.
Just
in the sense of assigned?  How is that?
As a lawyer, I just don't quite understand the concept.
The article is attributed.
Ah, good.  The article attributed to him is something that
he did not violate, but he must be
held accountable for it.  That is,
uh,
by decision of someone,
higher-ups, they
simply told him, well, they said what
and what was attributed to him?
15 days and 50,000 more per month, probably.
No, no, they attributed some kind of violation to him
, which he did not violate.
No, no, that's not said, as if it were
unknown.
Look, I, look, as a lawyer, it’s
a little scary for me to hear you
speak so calmly, right?  Ah, well, like they
just attributed to him a violation that he
didn’t commit, yes, but he should be held
accountable for it.  That's what you said, did
I hear you correctly?   Yes.   Do
you think this is normal?
If this person had simply been driving, he would have been
detained, and this, yes, this is not normal,
but since I am still,
probably, more on the
side of politics here, and if this were
some relative of mine, my godfather,
and a similar situation happened, I probably would
not communicate with my uncle anymore
, if he is Ukrainian, then what you did
not communicate with.  That's one thing.  Well, that is, you
think that in your country, Russia, it is
normal that the police, yes, can
charge a person with an offense
that he did not commit, and put him in jail
for 15 days for this offense.
Yes,
yes,
well yes.  Well, that is to say, this is
Okay, let's up the ante.  Can
law enforcement officials, for political reasons,
attribute a crime to
someone that he did not commit and
sentence him to three years in prison?
Yes, this can happen.
Well, do you think this is normal?
Well, something that he didn't do directly, well, if he was a
person who sat at home and did nothing, and they
attributed it to him, then, well, no, not like him, let's
say, he's clearly there, he doesn't
like Putin, he says there that the war
was unleashed against Ukraine unfairly,
that is, well, he says unpleasant things, he
writes publicly on the Internet.  Is it possible to
charge him with, for example, theft and have
him sent to prison for 3 years?   Yes.  Yes.
How do you see it?  How is this even
possible?
Well, well, they
probably won’t attribute anything to him here
.  You just called the situation a
discrediting of
both the Russian army and the
government, but that would be considered an
article.  Well, sort of
officially.  They
won't prosecute him for any theft.  They'll just
put him in jail.  Well, for the fact that he really...
That is, if a person says, yes,
this is what, uh, we shouldn’t fight with
Ukraine, yes, will they go to jail for this?
No, you won't go to jail for this.
So, if he comes out with a poster saying
stop the war, he will be
jailed.
Why?
Well, because it's more like,
well, if he just says in some
personal conversation or
on the phone there, I don't know,
talking to the camera and saying: "We
have to stop."   There
should be no war, that's one thing.  And when
you go out and publicly highlight it, you
can’t do that.
Interesting.
So, on the one hand, you're
telling me: "I haven't heard anyone in Crimea who's
for Ukraine, right?
But on the other hand, we've established that
everyone who's for Ukraine is against the war, and
you're in favor of, in short,
sending them to some prison."   Well, yes
.   Do
you think any Crimean
will tell you that he is for Ukraine?
In a private conversation it’s possible,
but
not in public, so to speak.
Well, look, what do you think, is Russia a
state based on the rule of law?
There is the rule of law and the
rule of law.   Yes.
But how does this relate to what you
said, that a person can easily be
accused of a crime that he did not
commit, for the reason that, well, it is
necessary?  And you even think it's
normal.  Yes, this is corruption.  This is
called corruption,
which exists in absolutely every country.
Well, do you think it’s normal, yes,
to charge a person with some kind of crime because of his political
beliefs
?
[sighs]
Well, it's
50/50 depending on the situation.  Well, that's my
personal opinion.  Yes
, yes, I’m asking about something personal, I’m
interested.
Well, it's 50/50.  It depends on the situation.  That
is, well, everyone’s situation is different, that’s
understandable.  Depends on the situation for me.
And how do you feel about the fact that Navalny was
also caught in the same way, they committed a
crime he didn't commit,
shoved him behind bars and left him to rot there?
How do you feel about this?
This is, of
course, vital and normal,
because
[clears throat] [cough]
he went for the wrong person, just like
Yevgeny Prigozhin.  Also,
well, these people are
not the same.  Yevgeny Prigozhin took the
armed route.
Well,
Navalny simply acted within the law.
Criticizing the government is not prohibited.
They started doing what was
not allowed.   What do you
mean it's impossible?
Well, he crossed,
so to speak, if we calmly
talk in ordinary language, he crossed the road
in the wrong place and in an unnecessary car.
So he did something that
contradicted the Constitution of the Russian
Federation.
No.
So, that is, he acted strictly
within the laws of the Russian Federation?
Well, penetration, I don’t know if
this can be considered penetration into the territory.
I don't know
what trespassing is.  and
the lighting,
how can I say, uh, of
houses, castles, villas, of
those people who are very
high-ranking in our country.
So, am I correct in understanding that you
support the idea that, yes, Navalny
was arrested on a fictitious charge, thrown behind
bars, and left to rot there?  Yes.
Well, he ended up the way he
shouldn't have, but he
went for it himself.  He, I’m not saying who was going to what, he
understood the risks, yes, that he could be killed and
so on, yes.  I'm asking you, do you
think the
Russian state and Russian
law enforcement agencies did the right thing by
fabricating a case against him and putting him in jail
?
Well, they didn't have a choice.  They
would have no choice.  They can't.
I'm not asking about their choice, I'm
asking about your choice now.  Do you
think they did the right thing or the
wrong thing?
Right.
Understood.
Mo, maybe my
internal policy may
not suit many people.  Mm, but
I'm like that actually.  Well, I
understand that you, among other things, are
not satisfied with her.  And how do you
feel about the fact that there was another
person who sort of
crossed the road in the wrong place, yes, as you
say, Nemtsov.  Yes, Nemtsov was also
against Putin and he was shot right in the
center of Moscow.  How do you
feel about this?
So, how should we feel about this?
Here.  Well, it's exactly the same.  The same
situation, similar to Navalny.  It's just that
the one who suffered more, the other one finished right away.
So, do you think the government
did the right thing by eliminating
Nemtsov?
Well, it’s a
difficult question, whether it’s right or not
.
I like tough questions, right?
You constantly speak correctly,
incorrectly.  And I don’t... And I don’t understand.  Well,
I didn't really think about whether it was right.  Well,
I don’t know, it’s natural, or something
.  Well, let's
put it this way, if you were in
Putin's place, would you also have given the order
to liquidate Nemtsov or not?
Yes, probably yes.
Probably yes.  Honestly, I won't lie to you.
Probably yes.  Probably the same.
And yet you think that Russia is a
democratic state governed by the rule of law?
Well, on paper, yes.
I'm not talking about papers, but reality based
on facts.
Well, yes, but here's the
question.  Look, what do you
think, if it works like this in Russia,
that with the snap of a finger you can fabricate a
case against anyone, put them in jail, kill them, right?
If some official, yes, sets his sights
on your parents' business, and,
uh, they fabricate a case against you, and your parents are
accused of putting you behind bars, how will you feel about
that?
E, naturally, is negative and bad.  Well, that was
unexpected.
Well, that's life.  Well, well, what about you, well, what about you,
can’t you do anything about it?  Well,
he did it, but he did it.  Well, what
will you do?
I'm not talking about something that can't be helped.  I
say: “What do you think, is it right
or wrong for the state to
do this?”
Well, what can we do?  Well,
well, naturally,
negatively, naturally, and badly.
But God willing, I hope that such a situation does not
happen.
That is, look, I get it right, I
understand that in your own country you are essentially
like slaves.  You are completely dependent on the will of
some people who can
manage your lives as they
wish.  So?
Well, no, that's probably an exaggeration.   Let's do it this way
.
They can, like, some people in
law enforcement
agencies, they can, uh, control
your lives, throw you in
jail, kill you.  Is that how it works?
Well, if you are an ordinary, peaceful person
who
doesn’t do everything that is
prohibited, so to speak, not at the
legislative level, and
everyone, everyone understands perfectly well what is
prohibited and what is permitted,
then you will be as pure as a
baby.  And if you violate this, be
prepared to take responsibility for it.
Yes, but the thing about police lawlessness is
that they can even
spank a baby.  Is it true?  That is, the steamroller
of repression does not distinguish between clean and
unclean.  So, an official wanted it,
for example, your mother will be liked by some
FSB guy, yes, and your dad and you,
for example, will be reproached for being behind bars, your business will be
taken away, and your mother will be,
well, for you, to prevent this from happening,
you also need to have
enough connections behind your back, so as
not to get into such situations, so that
everything goes smoothly. And in our country,
connections decide a lot.  So many.
That is, in Russia, in order
not to be killed illegally, or imprisoned, you don’t need to
have connections.
And money.  Yes.
Interesting,
huh?  Well, it turns out that someone with higher connections can always come along
and trample you, right?  And you think this is
normal?
These are the laws of nature or
Yes, well, let's take, for example, take
Europe, yes, take Germany.  Do the
same laws of nature apply there,
or are the laws of society somehow different?
Well, others.
So why can't they just take
someone and arrest them for some
trumped-up charge?
Well, they have such and such orders, different orders.
Understood.  Listen, why don’t you like
Ukrainians?  And why do you support the
war against Ukraine?  What did they
do to you?  You lived in Volgograd all your
life.
Well,
this is the first thing that,
you know, a
Russian actor who is no longer
alive, Sergei Bodrov, came as a young man.
He starred in the film "Brother".  Mm,
in one of the interviews he said, in
my opinion, very correct words.
If your country is at war,
no matter whether it is right or wrong,
you must be for your country.   Yes.
And I support, I support these
words.  I am of the same
opinion.   A
question right away.  But there was another country,
uh, in the thirties, forties of the 20th
century, the Third Reich, right?  Should
Germans have supported
Hitler's policies simply because it was their
country?
Well, it
seems so. Yes.  Fine.  If tomorrow your
country, yes, decides to drop a nuclear bomb
on Kyiv, you will also support it,
because it is your country.  Yes.   Yes.
Interesting.
Fine.  If tomorrow your country, uh,
wants to destroy Azerbaijan and you, the entire
male population of Azerbaijan,
will you also do so, simply because the
country decided so?
It turns out that yes.   Have
you ever thought that there might be some idiot at the head of the country
who
acts against the interests of the country's residents
?
If I am
convinced myself that this is really the case,
and some psycho is acting
against,
acting for, well, to the detriment of his own
people from his own country, then I will
reconsider the policy.
Okay, let's go.  So, if tomorrow the Kremlin
decides that, for example, 90% of Volgograd are
foreign agents, and wants to drop a nuclear weapon
on Volgograd, you will also
support it, because your country
decided this.
Well, well no
, well you are something out of
science fiction now.
Well, the whole of Azerbaijan is not a
fantasy for you, right?
Well,
well, I was kind of responding to Azerbaijan,
but like, well, anyway, yes, it’s
fantasy, but these are just some
fantastic, in fact, stories
that
Well, wait, five years ago
the bombing of Ukraine, those were also
fantastic stories.   Yes.
Well, I agree, partly.  Well,
if if if this happens,
then I will be against it, and you will see that it is
good.  And if your country, yes,
decides to make gas
chambers for a certain
nationality, like the Third Reich, for example, Ukrainians, yes,
because they are there, we are at war with
Ukraine, yes, and for Ukrainians it will be necessary to
make concentration camps in Russia, yes, and
gas chambers and so on.  You
will support it too, because it was your
country that decided so,
right?
Cool.
I support it as
long as it doesn’t concern
me and my family.   Well, yes
.  So until the cop gets to
you, you don't care, right?  So far, the repressions do
n't concern you.   Yes.  Yes.
How old are you, by the way?
21.
21 years old.   Yes.
You are already so spoiled.
Why use?
Well, from my point of view, we simply have
different worldviews.
Well, well, so
I understand correctly that you
were born under Putin and, in fact,
you never knew life without Putin?
No,
for me everything is a product of the Putin era,
you could say.
Well, yes, as well as a very large number of
people.
Cool.
Born under Putin, lived under Putin.
If I had died under Putin, I would have
died completely.  Well, I don’t, I don’t, I’m not tempted by the fact that
I will die under Putin.  It would also be
cool if it
turned out like this, you know, like he completely
invested in the Putin era.   Well, how is it
?
And has your girlfriend ever told you
that you...
No, well, I'm calm on my own.  Well, he is a
calm, kind person in himself.
I always help.   I
always help people.
And if you go, look,
imagine, you got married, yes, with her,
you say that the wedding is coming soon, right?  You
got married, that's it, you're already living, you have a
child there, right?  And then she says that she
has sorted out the war situation there, and she
believes that
she is for Ukraine.
What will you do?   I do
n't even know, honestly.  Well, well, well,
maybe, well, really in a
family, you know, sometimes
someone gets all caught up in religion, but she
watches Ukrainian TV channels,
Telegram channels, and says: "Damn,
why are we bombing them? We're wrong."
I, well, how can I say it, probably so that
she doesn’t tell me anything like that anymore
and stops
watching all this nonsense,
yes, she will already have an opinion formed in her head
, yes, she will, when you
say something there, oh, there
today, there we captured such and such a
village, yes, she will look at you so crookedly because of
this.  You will
feel it.
Well, I won't.  I will completely remove any talk
about
pro-war activities from colloquial speech.   I
'll stop talking to her about this.   Yes.   Sometimes I do it as a
joke.  Sometimes I can, like, tell a
joke there, yeah, you, damn, you, damn,
you, damn, I, well, like, it’s all a joke
, but it’s cool.  And you don't jokingly...
Well, then jokingly give her a
light slap on the back of the head.  Why,
why should it?
Well, I don’t know, there, because for some reason
you call her names as a joke.  Well, maybe I should
give him a flick on the cheek too.
Yes, not a
net for a fight.   I don't
allow myself to do anything like that.  Not yet
.  Well, not before the wedding yet.  Yes.   Yes.
Well, it's never her, is it that
you're Ukrainian or something?   No no no.
Well, it’s like this, you know, there are some
internal
jokes and gags between us.  And so, well, we always kind of
laugh about this.  There I am sitting
there, you know what?  And I don't love you.  He
says: "Why are you Ukrainian, it turns out
?"  Here.  Well, we kind of
laugh about it too.  And where did
she come from naturally
?  She is completely Russian.  Everything, everything is
Russian.  There is no connection with Ukraine at all
.
Well, where is she from?
With Volgograd.
From Volgograd, yes.  But imagine, it
turns out that when you get married, she just
loves you and is afraid to tell you that she is
really Ukrainian.  Yes.  Just imagine, uh
,
you get married, you have a child, and she
says: “Listen, I was afraid to tell you this
, to confess, because I
love you very much and have loved you, I didn’t want
us to separate.”  My parents are
Ukrainian, yes, it turns out that they
came to work in
Volgograd from the Lviv region during the Soviet Union, right?
How are you saying that she is Ukrainian, will she
be held accountable for
not saying this, for remaining silent, more
for this silence.
Then there won't be any questions.  I
love her as a person.  Can you
imagine that her ancestors
could have fought in the UPA together with Bandera?
It seems, imagine, that she is from the
Lviv region, from
some town there, I don’t know what they have there
in Lviv.  And her grandfather, yes, was with
Bandera.  Then, when
Soviet power came, my grandfather was sent
to Siberia, then he returned to Volgograd
and, in short, she was born there and so
on.  So here she is, a Bandera member
.
Well,
you have a son, you’re holding
the baby, right?  He's 3 months old, right?  She
says: "His great-grandfather was with Bandera
:
"Well, how do I, how do I feel about it?" Well, I'm
telling you, well, I'll feel the same way. Well, like,
more. Why? Why did you
keep quiet about it? Well, well, I know
her family chain very well, no, there's
no such thing there. Well, well, well,
you know, there are skeletons in the closet,
of course they'll come up with them. Nobody will
say in Volgograd, yeah, that their
grandfather was Bandera, yeah, for example.
Well, as for me, I'm no longer interested in my grandfather or directly about my great-grandfather
. That is, for
example, I, I do
n't even know who fought in my family, for example, in the
Great Patriotic War, because my
grandparents, my mother and I,
they were actually born in Petropavlovsk-
Kamchatsky. That is, they were in Kamchatka.
That is, look, I'll tell you
a secret now. The thing is that  The Far
East, Khabarovsk Krai, uh, Primorsky
Krai, Sakhalin, and Kamchatka, yes, 73%
were populated since the time of the Russian
Empire by immigrants from Ukraine. That is, they
were given out land there, yes, and people from
Ukraine moved there, that is, with a high
probability, yes, they could be
Ukrainians, because they
didn’t move from Russian provinces. They would have had
land anyway. The policy of the Russian
Empire was such that
German colonies were colonized there, and Ukrainians were
happily doing so. So it turns out,
what will happen if you find out that
you’re Ukrainian?
Well, nothing will change. So, what’s
your name, what’s your last name?
Ukrainian, Russian? My last name is
me. My last name is just like Caesar.
Caesar is my last name. I’m Caesar
Pavel. My last name is Caesar. It’s
not Caesarev, not Tsezaryuny, but
Caesar.
So,  Wait, have you ever seen a Russian
with the last name Caesar?
Well, everyone who knows me has
probably seen one.
But are there those in Kamchatka
with the last name Caesar?
No.
What's the last name of one?
One person. And they are Kornovs. Kornov, Kornov,
Kornov. And Caesar, I'm
really curious now, I'll look up Caesar, what kind of last name am I? I
mean,
I can show you official
documents, but I don't know. I believe it, I believe it. Yes, it's
just possible that you are, well, not Russian.
Well, I
don't know, the Greek community is larger. It's possible that you are Jewish
.
Well, then I am Jewish.
So.
[clears throat]
That's funny, Caesar.
Everyone is always surprised.
Here are the Jewish and German roots. So the
last name Caesar is found among Jews or
Germans who resettled in Russia. These
could be transformations of the last name, like
Kaiser, Caesar, right? In Russia, the last name
Caesar is very rare.  Yes. According to the
Federal Security Service databases, there are several dozen, hundreds at most
.
So it turns out you're not Russian. Well, you've always
been Russian, can you imagine?
Caesar in Rus'.
Yeah, right.
What's the girl's last name? Maybe she has a
Ukrainian one?
No, no, she's Koryakina.
Koryakina. Well, that's not a Russian last name.
Koryak - there's
no word for Koryak in Russian. What is
that? Let me look it up.
Koryakina or Koryakina?
Koryakina.
It's assumed
that it's related to the Koryak people or
refers to Korean origin. The
Koryak people are historically connected with
the peoples who lived in the area of
territory that is part of today's Russia.
In short, you're not Ukrainian, huh?
No, no,
damn, you're lucky.
Well, that's
cool then.
[laughter]
And what are you studying to be or what do you work as?
I'm
studying at the cadastral office. Well, land.
Land.
Ah, I don't work. I have  There's
no need to work yet,
while studying is more focused on studying. And
how old is the girl? If you're 21.
The girl is 20.
20. So, are you already planning to get married?
Yes, we have been in a
relationship with her for four years now. I proposed to her when she
received her diploma. We
studied together in
secondary vocational
education. And I proposed to her at the graduation ceremony
and that's it
. And we're having a wedding next year.
Cool. Well, if you live until
next year, because, well,
maybe, we did say that he was born under
Putin and lived under Putin and Priputin died.
Maybe Putin will kick the bucket this year
and you too. Well, anything can happen. It's like that
.
Well, naturally, it's just,
well, it's just,
well, like you step onto the wrong road. Not
in front of the wrong car, as they say.
Well, yeah,
it turns out, yeah.
Interesting, yeah, damn. But just
imagine, such a situation, right? Uh  Some
guy, the son of a policeman, the son of an
FSB agent, yeah, he'll like your
girlfriend.
Yeah.
Yeah. And he'll want to be with her, but for
that he'll have to eliminate you. Yeah.
If against this background, yeah, they throw
you some kind of trap and say you're a
drug dealer or a drug hoarder and they
throw you in jail for 5 years, and in the meantime he'll
be building a relationship with her.
How are you going to think this is normal? Is
this the law of life?
Well, I won't allow it.
How can I not allow it? So they arrested an
FSB agent. Son, they arrested you, found a
pack of drugs on you, and so
on.
Well, I have connections, and to be honest
,
I have quite a few connections,
and I think I can prove my case.
What connections? You're a 21-year-old
guy, what connections do you have?
Well, I'm not going to brag about my connections,
but I've made a lot of connections in my
life. These are my friends, and a
lot of connections from  parents.
Like, so you're sure that their connections
will be stronger? Yeah,
I think so, I think so. I think that,
well, I told you, there's one of the most
important things in the country, and that's money and
connections.
Yeah.
That's all.
Well, don't you think that when
some people's interests were transferred, yeah, in
Russia, neither big
money nor big connections helped, because
those people had big money and big
connections.
Well, that means I think that everything that's
done is for the best. That means that's how
my destiny was. [snorts] I
wish you such a destiny
.
Well, you wish me bad things. For what?
Maybe you'll even reconsider your
outlook on life in a good way. Well, you wish me such bad things.
What?
Why?
Well, it seems to me that's not the best thing.
Well, you're just looking at the situation,
it's just like that, and you're just
trying to push me down. Well,
that's life, that's life.
Well, you're just acting on my
moral standards.
What do you want? Yes.
Okay. It's up to you.
Well, I want, let's say, I have a
philosophy, yes, that there would be fewer people with such a
human-hating mindset
in the world. Well, you condemn such
thinking, right?
Yes. If, let's say, well, you don't
exist, if you... Well, that's cool, well,
damn, the world will be a better place.
Well, the world will be better if...
No, probably not the world. Probably, our
country will be better if, for example,
we remove
certain nations from here, so to speak,
for example, which nations should be removed from Russia
?
Nations. Well,
I mean, they are the indigenous people of
the Russian Federation. They are
descended from the Indians. And
so, wait, stop, stop, stop. They have lived on
the territories of Russia since time immemorial.
Well, what difference does it make whether they lived or not. But the
very point is that they need to be removed.
Wait, look. In the
Volgograd region, yes, Russians
appeared somewhere around 500 years ago, only
in the Volgograd region lived
much  before.
Yeah.
So why do you think that they do
n't deserve to live in the Russian
Federation?
Why do they deserve to live?
Because they are the only
citizens of the Russian Federation. Well,
that's not enough.
Very well. What other nations wouldn't
you want to see living in Russia?
90% Muslims. What do you
mean? Well, you have Muslims, citizens of
the Russian Federation and have been since time immemorial, right?
Caucasian peoples, Tatars, Bashkorts.
90% is
their original land. Look, you
live in Volgograd, right? These are the original
lands of Muslims. That was the Golden
Horde. Turkic peoples lived there. So,
you captured them. And now you're still saying
that they don't deserve to live in Russia.
Yes, that's right
.
So, you think... Wait,
I'm afraid to ask you. So, you
think that Ramzan Kadyrov doesn't deserve
to live in Russia?
Let's skip this question, let's do it. [laughter]
But you have connections.
[laughter]
Well, you're a little  You don't understand what
connections. [laughter] They
immediately untied the connections.
Ramzan Kadyrov deserves to live in Russia. He
[laughter]
is bombing.
No, quickly get his bearings right away. Listen. The
guts immediately untied themselves in the middle and
tied themselves up. Well done
. Well done. Damn, [laughter]
damn, you immediately brought up
something that upset me. The gopiy about Muslims seems
normal.
Good. For example, Chechnya, yes, a
Muslim region. Do you think
90% of
the population of Chechnya deserves to live in Russia?
Well, I think that it is only possible
that they should be
formed only in Chechnya. What do you
mean? That is, for example, Russians
can travel anywhere in Russia, but Chechens
only in Chechnya?
Yes. That's
why be in Russia then?
Because, because, because that's what the
authorities want. I don't know why
not. What do you think? Well, what do you
think? It turns out, as I
understand it, that you want  Chechens
lived only in Cheysray. They should
be a separate country, in my opinion.
That's against the integrity of the Russian
Federation. How so?
Well, you see how I walk sometimes.
Good. And Tatarstan should be a
separate country?
Uh, no.
So, why should Chechnya, in your opinion,
be separate? Tatarstan? No,
Chechnya is still completely separate,
separate, so to speak,
like a continent
from the Russian Federation, which live
[clears throat] [cough] completely by
its own laws and
its own legal actions. And
Tatarstan is, you could say, a direct
Russia. What do you
mean? But here, you say it yourself,
everyone lives by their own actions. Any
cops can do whatever they want.
Well, I have nothing to do with that. It's more
about the law.
In Chechnya, it's
good. Ingushetia should become a separate
country.
I'll shut up about Ingushetia.
So it's just like... And Dagestan
should become a separate country?
[clears throat]
No.
Why?
Because I love Dagestan. I love
Dagestanis.
So, you don't like Chechens?
No.
Wait a minute. I don't understand, why? Well,
why do you love them?
What's the basis for this? You want to
ask?
What? What is
it? What's the basis for this?
And what's the basis for the fact that you
love Dagestanis but don't like Chechens?
Well, because they kill our
Russian women and
for them it's normal, but for them, killing a pig is
haram. I
mean, where are Chechens killing Russian
women?
Where? All over Russia, there are
newcomers, well, these, what should we call them
exactly, who
do all this, these are the ones who
allow themselves to do this to girls.
So, do Russians in Russia rob women?
For example, I watched, a representative of the
Wagner PMC killed a schoolgirl there and so
on.
Well, well, yes, that's more of a rhetorical question
.
For example, I haven't heard of
anyone from Akhmat's regiment killing women.
Well,
let's put it this way. Am I right in understanding
that Russians aren't Chechens?
No, I said that's all true.
But what's the reason you have
problems with Chechens?
Well, I, you know, some of
their, some of these rules,
you know,
come here or there on the street, or
I, well, I can even observe this with
my own eyes all the time. You
can go on Telegram publics and
constantly see something, yes, they're up to something
in that country, in which,
yes, as you said, they were the
successors of this country, but
fate has it that there are far fewer of them
than Russians, and so there would
be less of this, such as this. Less of
them should be removed from here.
And how, how do you propose, how
should they be removed? They are citizens of
the Russian Federation, yes, they live in
Russia, in Moscow, there, in St. Petersburg, in
Volgograd. How should they be removed?
I don't know that yet. I have
n't thought about that yet.
Well, that's also not  It's not easy, yeah, to just pick
off that many people.
They're organized grown men, after all
. You're not going to go and
get rid of them, are you?
How can I get rid of them? I'd put them on a plane and,
like,
sign up for some Russian community to get rid of non-
Russians there, you know
, a Russian community, which, well
, why, why would it be possible,
I don't have any, I'm not afraid of
these bearded guys,
so you probably still support
Stalin's deportation, right? That
Chechens loaded train cars with Ingush and
deported them all to Kazakhstan, right? I
barely support Stavlena.
Well, support the deportation of
Chechens? I did
n't support it at all.
Well, he did exactly what you
want: take them all and, in short,
catch them somewhere out of sight.
Or do what Hitler did, what
he did with the Jews. Same thing.
Listen, what other peoples
in the Russian Federation bother you?
I get it. So you don't like the Russians, you know
, but who else?
Well, there are probably no others like that. Kalmyks are
fine, I guess. Who else do we have? Tatars,
Ukrainians.
Ukrainians
who support Russia are fine. Well,
any Ukrainian living in Russia definitely
supports Russia.
Well, why? For example, Ukrainians,
yes, many of them who live in Russia, have
cousins, second cousins ​​in Ukraine,
because they
came during the Soviet Union, yes, and they,
for example, say: "Yes, I can't
support the war against Ukraine
because my relatives are there." How do you
feel about these people?
Be neutral. I'm fine with it
. If he's neutral, then that's
fine. If he's for Ukraine, I'll tell him
then.
But since he's a citizen of the Russian Federation,
how can you tell him? I'm saying it's his
birthright to be here.
No, well.  Wait, then you are here
if you are for Ukraine and you are in the
country that is your Ukraine here
. And he will tell you: "Look,
this is not Ukraine, Russia, this is Russia
Ukraine." Russia attacked Ukraine.
Well, well, then why
are you here and living and paying taxes? Well
, look, he says that we
must stop the war against Ukraine and that's it
. After
shooting
then.
So you kick him out, in short, from somewhere.
Well, I mean, I am driving him away from
this war then. You tell me this then, "hate me."
Why did you bother him at all? I can't
understand this scheme.
Yes, I mean, harassed him. Well, you
said it yourself. Here's an example. You just
gave me an example. I'll just say the same way
, as I don't know how
to, for example, uh,
I'm from Azerbaijan, yes. How have
you been persecuting
Azerbaijanis in Russia for the last week? How do you
feel about Azerbaijanis in Russia?
I have a former friend,
we talked  with him for a while. He himself is from
the backyard.
Yeah. A
former friend, did I understand correctly? A former
friend, right?
Yes, yes, yes. Well, no, no, it's not
justified by any reason,
it's just, well, a friend with whom I
communicated well for a while. He's
from Baku himself. His parents are, well,
like, Azerbaijanis, purebred,
so everything is fine with that.
And, well, I, in fact, I was, so to
speak,
inspired by him, because he was the
first
very, very non-Russian, like, well, how
to say, very non-Russian person that I
met in my life. And I
liked
everything and, in principle, his vision.
and the hospitality of him and his brother. That is
, well, it's something on the level of
fantasy. I really
liked it, and I...
Yes, and and
and what is it, well, that it's not that we don't have anything like
they do. Well, that is
,
that they are hospitable and so on,  Yes.
So how do you feel about Azerbaijan?
Your microphone is something else. It's
hissing a lot
now. Normal.
No,
[music]
the microphone is normal now.
Well, it's like you pronounce the words and
then only you speak with your lips.
Ah, well, once, once, once. Now.
Well, also
wait a bit.
Just now, just now, just now it seemed to be
normal.
No,
when they told me to wait, at that
moment it was normal.
Now it's normal.
Well, yes.
Okay. So how do you feel about
Azerbaijanis in Russia?
Normal. Normal.
To those who don't break the laws.
Normal. Mm, who don't break
the laws. There are
no such things.
And as for Chechens, who don't break the
laws,
those 10% are normal.
Ramzanka is included in that 10%. Yes,
of course.
That is, Ramzan Kadyrov does not break
the laws of the Russian Federation.
And I'll give you an example. For example, you
had a guy named Nikita Zhuravel in your Volgograd
. Yes,
Yes, I know, but for me, I want to say right away
, this is yes, this is [ __ ] absurd,
of course.
[laughter]
Well, look, let me just remember for myself
. He did some action there,
burned the Koran. If he did something wrong
, he should have been punished there according to
the laws of the Russian Federation. Well, the Chechens
took him from Volgograd, took him to
their pre-trial detention center in Chechnya, yes, they brought in young
Ramzanka, this
fifteen-year-old Kadyrov, and he
just beat him like a punching bag on camera. And
then the dad, uh, the head of Chechnya, yes, he
posted it on Instagram, yes, that is,
they are not afraid of anyone. And you all
kept silent, all of you.
What can we do?
We're trying. It's hard to get through. It
happens.
How are you [laughter] going to drive these Chechens there to
Chechnya, if it's still hard to swallow
?
Well, only in words.
Only on  in words
exactly. Only in some kind of your own stupid
world.
So it turns out that you can burden a girl who sings a
song in Ukrainian,
right? But to protect the
same Russian guy from the same
Volgograd, yes, like you, you [snorts]
all op.
And how can I protect him?
Well, I don’t know, get together with
like-minded people, hold some kind of rally.
Vernita
killed them. And what will change from this?
Who will kill them?
I think they will be found.
Who? The police, or what?
No, the
Chechens,
I think. Yes. What do you
mean? That is, if you are in Volgograd,
you go out, hold a rally, return
Nikita Zhuravl, like, to the Volgograd pre-trial
detention center, yes, because according to the law, yes,
you will be beaten, yes, there.
Yeah.
Cool. So it turns out, as
I understand it, look, what if for a
girl who sings in Ukrainian,
you should be beaten, then you'll also stop
making comments to the girl?
No,
I get it. The problem is that, uh, they'll beat
you up for, uh, Adamka Kadyrov, but for
a girl who sings in Ukrainian, they
won't beat you up yet. It's necessary that,
well, it's one thing, well, after all, these are
different violations, the people who did it.
One,
I get it. Look, the fact that you're afraid of
Kadyrov, I understand, I understand, I do
n't need to detail it and make excuses. I
understand that you're high and you understand
that the volume of your connections is somehow not
quite enough. Yeah,
no one has enough. No one has
enough. That's it
. You're so straight up, no one has enough
. No one has enough.
No one has enough. That's it.
Yeah. You got so excited. Not
enough. You understand, you even felt
that bottle right on you, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Did it
hurt inside?
No,  I
understand.
I've always understood that. Everything is fine.
Don't you think that in this country you're
just a
No.
How do you get along there in your head? Am
I right in understanding that if tomorrow
Adam Kadyrov wants your girlfriend, yes, for his
own misfortune, yes, they'll
come and take her away, they'll give you a
hard time, and you won't be able to do anything in
Russia. Yeah.
Uh, probably yes. I guess I
understand correctly.
And are you going to resign yourself to it then and just
live, well, look for another girl?
Yes. Yes.
No.
I
won't give up what's mine. As for,
well, how can you not give it up? Well, look,
they arrived in a Helicopter, in short, yes,
they loaded her up, in short, they told you to
starve there for two years, yes, they said,
like, if you make a move, we'll push
your knees, your hands, and so on and so forth.
That's it.
And what will you do? Will you go to Grozny for
her?
Let them do what they want.
I think I'm not going to die in this
case.  It's a shame. So
what are you doing? They
took everything away, that you're from Volgograd. There
you are, sitting in Volgograd, she's already in
Grozny. She's having a wedding there, in short,
another one with Kadyrov, yeah, she's going to be his
third wife there, right? And what are you
doing? You buy a ticket for the commuter train.
What are you doing?
You won't go to the police, because you
understand that they'll say, "Oh,
Kadyrov has connections, go, baby, have fun." I
'll go with a machine gun. How about a snowstorm, I'll
just do it, yeah, I
need to get a machine gun somewhere. And where will you
go? You'll be at a checkpoint, they'll
stop you, I'll clean up there, and they'll even
shove a machine gun right up to your eye.
I'll go to Chechnya, then I'll just
go somewhere. I'll eat Kadyrov's big
sing-along.
Maybe I'll go.
Got it,
right? Interesting, interesting.  Well, that's it.
I'm not from Azerbaijan.  , I'm from Ukraine.
I just stream with the
Azerbaijani flag.  I like.  I
support Azerbaijan because they are doing well
against Russia.  And you're an ordinary
Russian, which is 90% of
Russia, right?  And it’s very revealing how
afraid you are of Kadyrov.  Very revealing.
I liked it.  I could actually
feel, you know, the trembling in your
muscles.  They even transmitted this warmth
from them to me.  I'll say this,
uh, the time will come, and in Crimea people
will again calmly speak Ukrainian, and people like
you, the occupiers, will calmly
flee from there.  And in Volgograd there will soon be more non-Russians
than Russians.  And they are
organized, they are united, and people like
you will study, will study for the sake of it and so
on.  Your Russia will disintegrate,
including along Muslim regions and
along different territorial
administrative borders.
Here.
Well, I wish, as I wished for you, that
you were born under Putin, lived under Putin, and that
Putin lived longer than you.   Yes.
Fine.
Here is a
refined example of a Russian
Nazi.  And
they hate everyone
there, Chechens, Ukrainians and so on.
Yes, they live in the occupied
territories of Volgograd.  These are Turkic
lands.  They came there, why do you
live there, Crimea?  They arrived, he arrived
there for 3 years or lived there for 7 years and that’s it
.  He Why is this girl in
Ukrainian, if she sings, for him
he is glad that he will falsify the case against her and
will serve a sentence for something
that she did not commit.  That's all.
And whoever in Ukraine says: “Oh, well, stop
talking Russian, stop being surprised.
Russia blurts out everything else in Russian,
but here they are
tolerant.”
Mati Povna Ukraization of Ukraine like,
subscribe comment.  Yeah.